André Luis Ferreira

Florianópolis, Santa Catarina, Brazil



adnux182@gmail.com



(42)99962-8371



linkedin.com/in/andre-luis-ferreira

Summary

From boy scout to nature adventurer, from early web child to web developer. I'm a Senior Software Developer, living from the web dev.

Experienced as integrations engineer, scrum master, full-stack developer, i've been in lead front-end roles in the last 3 years.

Living by the agile mindset and looking to be always delivering good value, task by task.

Technologies: React & React Native, Javascript, Typescript, Reactive Architectures, Rest, Graphql, Websockets, Java, Spring, Microservices, Docker, AWS, Git and more.

Experience



Senior Software Engineer

Jul 2020 - Present (10 months +)

Started at Dextra as full Stack developer working allocated on a project for Dafiti (Global Fashion

The project started as a system where the store clients could apply for a credit card and later, giving back cashback in purshases with that card.

My initial role was to lead the front-end development in the team and after some time, I got at the Tech Owner role to help bridge business and technology, find ways to better integrate them, and also help the team to keep focus on technical solutions that meet the business needs.

The front-end was mainly React and Typescript, with a mix of context api and redux actions, formik, using graphql to query for data.

The back-end services were built in Java with spring boot, postgresql databases, some aws SQS queues helping to handle high traffic volume and more.

The services run on containers in a aws eks cluster, which used to be delivered with some internal tools but we are migrating them to ArgoCD.

All projects run in a CircleCI pipeline to automatically check if code style, tests, docker images publishing and app release are all working.

There was also some Golang on the graphql "gateway" and a PWA in a micro front-end architecture to deliver the front-end projects.

tino Mobile Application Developer

Tino App

Jan 2020 - Sep 2020 (9 months)

TinoApp is a Services App that works as market place for service providers and people needing those services to find each other.

Started to work on the project initially focusing on the Mobile development with React Native, updating and refactoring features and creating the new ones.

The main front-end technologies used were React Native, Typescript, Redux, Redux-Saga, Immutable, plus some other frameworks.

In the Backend of the app the development used Python 3+, Django and it's templates and migrations, Firebase cloud messaging, firestore, postgresql databases, postgis and more.

Software Developer

Softplan

Jan 2018 - Mar 2020 (2 years 3 months)

UNJ - PJ - Front End Specialist

- My main role in the team was to help team members to work with chosen front-end technologies, architectural patterns and best practices.
- Also had contributed with some back-end micro services best practices.
- Used to be involved in the selection of new front-end developers, to later mentor them in business or technology concerns.
- Used to work close to the PO and UX/UI team to transform product concepts and mockups in the final features of the new product being developed.
- Used to maintain the backend service, contributing to define and evolve endpoints, and to create or update some MongoDB queries.
- Helped them to start using Gitlab to keep and manage code and run continuous integration pipelines with docker containers.

e Sr. Software Analyst

Elotech Gestão Pública

Jan 2016 - Dec 2017 (2 years)

Evolução - Sr. Software Analyst (2016-2017):

- My role on this team was to work on the Oxy Platform, the new architecture defined to modernize the applications of the company.
- To do the job i was used to deal with technologies like Java with the latest of Spring framework (boot, cloud, data, rest), with Gradle handling the dependencies and build of the projects, managing the continuous integration pipeline with Jenkins and code quality with Sonar.
- The front end was built in React with ES6 and Redux one project and Angular 4 with TypeScript and RxJS on other project. The data repositories used to be Oracle or PostgreSQL and were accessed by Spring Data, RSQL, QueryDSL or pure SQL, depending on the need.

e Sr. Software Analyst + Scrum Master

Elotech Gestão Pública

Feb 2013 - Dec 2015 (2 years 11 months)

ARW (Arrecadação Web) - Sr. Software Analyst + Scrum Master (2013-2016):

- -My role on the team was to build Web solutions on Java language supported by technologies like Spring, Hibernate, Primefaces, Maven, using primarily Oracle 11g as data repository and managing the continuous integration pipeline with Jenkins and code quality with Sonar.
- In this team I also worked on the development of some systems integration to internal and external applications, all related to Public Management.
- By mid 2013 as the company adopted Scrum as the agile framework, i was put as the Scrum Master of the team working closely to the PO, Management and the Clients to gather requirements and receive feedback, orienting the team during reviews and plannings and other agile related matters.
- While in the role of SM the company passed thru the CMMI Level 2 certification successfully.

Software Analyst

HSBC

Jun 2012 - Jan 2013 (8 months)

HUB (HSBC Universal Banking) Front End - Software Analyst (2012-2013):

- My role on the team was to develop front end applications and features to the existing ones.
- The technologies used on the project included Java with Spring Framework, jUnit with other test libraries, WebSphere Application Server and MQ.
- The development environment had IBM tools like RTC and the team was using Scrum as the agile methodology.

Software Analyst

HSBC

Nov 2010 - May 2012 (1 year 7 months)

GBM DML (Data Modeling, Transformation and Integration) - Software Analyst (2010-2012):

- My role on the team was to develop system integrations mainly using Java with Spring Batch or Integration frameworks.
- These integration used to produce files to send thru a secured connection, or messages to be sent to queues or topics, with the receivers being on the same or other countries.
- The integrations included legacy and current applications used by the HSBC Group in countries like United Kingdom, Turkey, Mexico, Peru and others.
- On the role i also was in charge of creation of requirements and technical documentation, and once the project was done a "fire fighting" document used to be created to.

Software Developer

KMM | Inovup

Feb 2010 - Aug 2010 (7 months)

Web and Desktop developer in projects using ColdFusion (Adobe), Ajax, Delphi, Oracle 10g and other technologies.

Software Developer

Cartago Tecnologia

2008 - 2009 (2 years)

Web Developer, using technologies like PHP, MyQSL and jQuery on development of systems for logistics.

Education



📠 Federal University of Technology - Parana

Analista de Sistemas, Análise de Sistemas de Computação



FCV - Faculdade Cidade Verde

Especialização, Engenharia de Software 2014 - 2015

Especialização voltada ao estudos de processos, técnicas e metodologias para o desenvolvimento eficaz de softwares de qualidade, dentro dos prazos e custos pré-determinados.

Licenses & Certifications

Eneagrama aplicado ao dia a dia - IEneagrama Brasil

Skills

Java • Scrum • JavaScript • Software Engineering • Engenharia de software • Desenvolvimento de front-end • React.js • Spring Framework • Hibernate • Spring